# **Graeme Thornber**

**Mobile:** +6421 0292 4529

**E-mail:** gdthornber@gmail.com **Website:** www.thornberrypie.com

## **Profile**

Full-Stack Open-Source Web Developer with 12 solid years experience building and maintaining modern web applications in Auckland, Wellington and Bonn, Germany.

I've worked with some of New Zealand's top digital and design agencies on a range of projects with local and global clients. I write extensible, readable, reusable code in a variety of open-source languages, using a flexible array of Javascript and PHP-based CMS frameworks.

I'm also a musician and actor, playing mainly guitar and anything else with strings including piano. In 2018 I acted with Whitianga's Offbeat Theatre in my 5th play, and co-founded a local improv theatre group.

## **Education**

2005 – 2006 Natcoll (Auckland, New Zealand)

Diploma in Web Development

1992 – 1996 Howick College (Auckland, New Zealand)

English, Computer Studies, Drama, Music, Japanese

# **Employment History**

2017 - 2018

**Senior Remote Developer** 

DNA (Auckland, NZ) www.dna.co.nz

Working remotely in an Agile environment for clients mainly in the public sector on Silverstripe's CWP platform: <a href="www.business.govt.nz">www.fma.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.fma.govt.nz">www.fma.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.fma.govt.nz">www.fma.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.fma.govt.nz">www.fma.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.govt.nz">www.fma.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.govt.nz">www.greatjourneysofnz.co.nz</a>, <a href="www.govt.nz">www.greatjourneysofnz.co.nz</a>, <a href="www.govt.nz">www.govt.nz</a>, <a href="www.govt.nz">www.g

#### 2016

### **Lead Developer**

Spitfire: The Digital Agency (Auckland, NZ) <u>www.spitfire.co.nz</u>
Managing contractors and working across many projects and platforms, mainly with Concrete5 CMS.

www.roche.co.nz, www.cancerinfo.co.nz, www.chelsea.co.nz

#### 2014 - 2015

Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) <u>www.graemethornber.com</u>
Working with a variety of technology stacks for digital agencies including:
Colenso BBDO, RAPP (DDB), <u>Image Center Group</u>, <u>iDesignMedia</u>, <u>Insight Creative</u>, <u>J. Walter Thompson</u>, <u>Satellite Media</u>, <u>Touchcast</u>

2011 - 2013

Senior PHP Developer

Scopevisio AG (Bonn, Germany) - www.scopevisio.com

Building and maintaining the company's website in Drupal using Web Services with REST, SOAP, JSON and XML while also gaining an advanced knowledge of SEO.

www.scopevisio.com, www.centerdevice.de

#### 2010 - 2011

## **Lead Developer / Project Manager**

## +The Church+ (Wellington, NZ) - www.thechurch.co.nz

Building custom Wordpress themes and plugins for local and international clients, I took sole ownership of many projects - from initial scoping and architecture to building, deploying and maintaining bespoke content-management driven web applications.

Ngati Toa Rangatira, NZSO, RJ's Licorice, Toi Whakaari, Toyota

#### 2008 - 2010

### Front End Developer

Solutionists (Auckland, NZ) - www.solutionists.co.nz

During my time at Solutionists I worked on over 100 projects: from building HTML email templates and brochure campaigns to full corporate E-Commerce solutions for clients such as:.

Barkers, Huffer, Ministry of Health, Overland Footwear, Random House

#### 2007 - 2008

Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) - www.graemethornber.com

After completing my Diploma in 2006 I made the transition from hospitality to the web industry contracting for clients in Auckland including

Zest Media and Brown Paper Bag.

#### 1997 - 2006

Waiter, Bartender, Restaurant Supervisor, Event Manager

Bars, Restaurant and Events in Auckland:

Horse & Trap (Mt Eden), Kermadec (Viaduct), Kings Arms (Newton), Portofino (Mission Bay), Vivace (High St), White Horse Inn (Pakuranga) and London:

The Feathers (Westminster), The Jolly Gardeners (Putney)

## **Technical Skills**

Javascript: ¡Query, ES6, Node.js, Expres, ReactJS, AngularJS, Ember CSS3: SASS, LESS, Stylus, Flexbox, Compass, Normalize, PostCSS HTML5:, Bootstrap, Foundation, Pure, Twig, Mustache, Smarty PHP7: OOP, MVC, PSR-2, Laravel, Symfony, Zend, Codelgniter, CakepHp Data: MySQL, XML, JSON, CSV, MongoDB, Mongoose, Firebase, HeidiSQL **CMS**: Silverstripe, Wordpress, Drupal, Bolt, Concrete5, Joomla, Typo3 Agile & team tools: Git, Slack, Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Basecamp, Trello Accessibility: WCAG2, WAI-ARIA, WebAIM, WAVE, Axe, NVDA, VoiceOver CLI tools: NPM, Composer, Gulp, Webpack, Yarn, Babel, Grunt, Bower **E-Commerce**: Magento, Zen Cart, Shopify, WooCommerce, BigCommerce **Design tools**: Sketch, InVision, Photoshop, Fireworks, InDesign, Illustrator **Animation**: CSS Transitions & Keyframes, HTML5 Canvas, Flash Actionscript Web Services: AJAX, REST, cURL, AWS, Rackspace, SOAP, PEAR Google: Maps API, YouTube API, Search Console, Analytics, Adwords E-mail / PDF: Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, Litmus, Mandrill, CleverReach Server setup: Apache, Linux, DigitalOcean, MAMP, XAMPP, Plesk, cPanel **DevOps**: Capistrano, Jenkins, Beam, Beanstalk, Raygun, Graylog IDEs: Atom, Sublime Text, Xcode, PhpStorm, Notepad++, NetBeans, Eclipse

As well as the above I also have a very basic knowledge of: ASP.NET, C, C#, Java, Go, Python, Ruby, Swift

I'm currently learning:

Vue.js, TypeScript, Postgres, PostGIS and geospatial data mapping

# Other skills:

- Mastery of English with excellent formal and creative writing skills
- I'm involved in the theatre and run a bi-weekly improv group
- Over 25 years experience playing guitar and other instruments
- Can speak German and read / write Japanese
- Wit, personality and a sense of humour

Examples of my work can be found on my website at: www.thornberrypie.com